Guide to the Benno C. Schmidt, Jr., President of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Benno C. Schmidt, Jr., president of Yale University, records
1975-1994
1986-1994
RU 281
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
214.16
The records consist of subject files, correspondence, annual reports, and memoranda documenting Benno C. Schmidt's activities as president of Yale University. The records contain substantive documentation on virtually every aspect of the university administration, schools, departments, and other major units.
Yale University. President's Office
Schmidt, Benno C., 1942-
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the Yale president's office.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
Benno C. Schmidt, Jr., served as president of Yale University from 1986-1992.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of subject files, correspondence, annual reports, and memoranda documenting Benno C. Schmidt's activities as president of Yale University. The records contain substantive documentation on virtually every aspect of the university administration, schools, departments, and other major units.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; College presidents; Educators; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Presidents; Yale University. President's Office
- Records of the President, 1981-1993; Accession 2018-A-032
  - Academic units
    - School of Architecture, Koetter correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Department of Biology, correspondence, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Department of Computer Science, Rokhlin correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dean searches and appointment correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Department of Economics, Levin correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - School of Forestry and Environmental Science, Cohon correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Department of the History of Art correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - School of Law building plans, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - School of Management, Dean Levine correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - School of Medicine
      - Acting Dean Donaldson correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Dean appointment-Rosenberg, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Dean search, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Robert Gallo correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Incident correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - School of Music, Laderman appointment correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - School of Music, Dean Tirro correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - School of Nursing, future correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - School of Organization and Management, Dean Levine Institutional Understanding, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - School of Organization and Management, Dean Levine terms, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Department of Philosophy, Marcus correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Department of Philosophy faculty correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Department of Philosophy PPE program, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Yale College, Dean Altman salary, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 24A)
  - Administration
    - Development
    - Facilities-funding, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Facilities-Harkness Hall gate, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - General Counsel-development lawyer position, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Human Resources
      - Annual salary increase guidelines for Managerial and Professional staff, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Benefits for gay and lesbian partners, correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Graduate Employees and Student Organization (GESO) correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Labor issues, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Labor negotiations, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Managerial and Professional Classification and Compensation study, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - President
      - Correspondence, recommendations, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Correspondence, resignations, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - Schmidt administration-first four years, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - Speeches-Naples, Florida [video cassette], 1987 January 15 (Box 2)
      - Summary of activities, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Provost correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Vice President for Finance and Administration
      - Budget situation, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - Financial situation of the university, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Affiliated organizations
    - Center for International and Area Studies, Acting Director Foltz, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Centers for Technological Excellence, correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Institute of Sacred Music, director appointment-Cook, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Institution for Social and Policy Studies, Gordon memorandum on issues, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Arthur W. Wright Nuclear Structure Laboratory, Bromley correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Yale Alumni Magazine-interviews with Benno Schmidt
      - 1989 February 15
        - Part 1 (Box 3)
        - Part 2 (Box 4)
      - 1989 March 10
        - Part 1 (Box 5)
        - Part 2 (Box 6)
    - Yale Health Plan correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Yale Review, Erickson resignation, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Yale Review editor search, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Yale New Haven Hospital property costs, correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Yale New Haven Hospital, Zaccagnino correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Libraries, Galleries and Museums
    - Art Gallery requests, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Peabody Museum director search, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - University Librarian appointment terms, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - University Librarian reappointment, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Athletics, director resignation correspondence, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Awards, MacArthur fellowship correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Committees
    - Committee on Restructuring correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Investment Committee correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Labor Steering Committee recommendations, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Task force on communication "Keck Center", 1990 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - University Council Committee correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - University Council Committee on Biological Sciences, 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - University Council Committee on Communications, 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - University Council Committee on the Divinity School, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - University Council Committee on the Humanities-Literature, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - University Council Committee on the Institute of Sacred Music, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - University Council Committee on the School of Art, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - University Council Committee on the School of Drama, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Corporation
    - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Finance Committee, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Educational Policy Committee, Sociology Department, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Honorary degrees correspondence, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - President's agendas, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - General files
    - Alumni budget correspondence, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - B. Schmidt interview [audio cassette]
      - Part 1, Undated (Box 7)
      - Part 2, Undated (Box 8)
    - Celebration of Yale Generations [video cassette], Undated (Box 9)
    - Chaplain search, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Gay and lesbian students correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - From Corporate Rule to Civil Society-Korten [audio cassette], Undated (Box 10)
    - Griswold and Brewster papers project, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Letters of recommendation, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Male/Female equity correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - University President's roundtable [video cassette], 1988 April 18 (Box 11)
  - Government
    - President Bush correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - White House correspondence-Cabranes, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - New Haven, York-Chapel area correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Professorships
    - Recommendations, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Bird White Honsum Professor of English Literature correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Residential Colleges
    - Berkeley College, Master extension-Winks, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Calhoun College Master correspondence, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Master searches correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Pierson College Master correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Saybrook College Master appointment correspondence, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Ezra Stiles College Master correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 109)
- Records of the President, 1986-1992; Accession 2018-A-061
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2028.
  - President's House
    - Reception for new students, 1986 September 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Recurring events, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - New faculty reception, 1987 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - New faculty reception, 1987 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Reception for new students, 1987 August 29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - New faculty reception, 1987 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - New faculty reception, 1987 December 7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Reception for new students, 1988 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - New faculty reception, 1988 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - New faculty reception, 1988 December 7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - New faculty reception, 1989 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Reception for new students, 1989 September 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - New faculty reception, 1989 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Reception for Lou Cappiello, 1990 January 23 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Yale revisited, 1990 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Yale revisited, 1990 April 11 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Dinner for John Hall-Gordon Grand Fellow, 1990 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ved Mehta reception, 1990 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Master's dinner, 1990 May 9 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Reception for Dr. Rowe, 1990 June 4 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Medical School library dedication, 1990 June 7 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Reception for new students, 1990 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Yale University Women's Organization-wine and cheese reception, 1990 September 13 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Reception for Ogletree and Kavanaugh, 1990 September 24 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Connecticut Conference of Independent Colleges-John Rowland reception, 1990 October 10 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Connecticut Conference of Independent Colleges-Lowell Weicker reception, 1990 October 16 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - The Club dinner, 1990 October 17 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Yale revisited luncheon, 1990 October 26 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - New faculty reception, 1990 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - New faculty reception, 1990 November 7 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Dinner for Saudi ambassador, 1990 December 3 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Reception for Peabody directors, 1990 December 10 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Woodbridge Hall holiday party, 1990 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Dinner for L. Bass, 1991 February 13 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Dinner for Robertson Davies, 1991 February 20 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Reception for elected officials, 1991 February 26 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Yale revisited luncheon, 1991 March 8 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Yale revisited dinner, 1991 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Dinner for Lee and Ramona Bass, 1991 April 17 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Dinner for Mr. and Mrs. Perry Bass, 1991 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Master's dinner, 1991 May 7 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Reception for Mary Griswold, 1991 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Reception for Lloyd Richards, 1991 June 3 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Reception for new students, 1991 August 31 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Reception for Georges May, 1991 September 13 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Dinner for J. Pollitt, 1991 September 16 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Reception for Worth David, 1991 September 20 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Yale revisited luncheon, 1991 September 26 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Dinner for A. John Anlyan, 1991 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - New faculty reception, 1991 October 9 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - New faculty reception, 1991 October 10 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Yale revisited luncheon, 1991 October 15 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Yale revisited luncheon, 1991 October 25 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Dinner before the airing of "Lethal Innocence" on PBS, 1991 February 13 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Yale revisited luncheon, 1992 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Buffet dinner, 1992 February 21 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Cocktails for faculty, 1992 March 3 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Dinner for Anita Hill, 1992 April 2 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Dinner for Stephanie Spangler, 1992 April 2 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Reception for Harry and Manette Adams, 1992 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Master's dinner, 1992 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Reception for Dean Gordon, 1992 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Dinner for Harry Wellington, 1992 June 2 (Box 2, Folder 50)